Bitter Harvest is a war, drama, history film directed by George Mendeluk.
Set between the two World Wars and based on true historical events, Bitter Harvest conveys the untold
story of the Holodomor, the genocidal famine engineered by the tyrant Joseph Stalin.
The film displays a powerful tale of love, honour, rebellion and survival at a time when Ukraine was
forced to adjust to the horrifying territorial ambitions of the burgeoning Soviet Union.
Yuri, played by Max Irons.
Natalka, played by Samantha Barks.
Ivan, played by Terence Stamp.
Yaroslav, played by Barry Pepper.
Sergei, played by Tamer Hassan.
Mykola, played by Aneurin Barnard.
Bitter Harvest is a 2017 period romantic-drama film set
in Soviet Ukraine in the early 1930s.
The film is the first English language feature film
depicting Ukraine's famine, the 1932–33 Holodomor.
The film stars Max Irons, Samantha Barks, Barry Pepper,
Tamer Hassan, Lucy Brown and Terence Stamp.
The film was directed by George Mendeluk.
The story and screenplay were written by Canadian
screenwriter-actor Richard Bachynsky Hoover.
Filming took place in and around Kyiv, Ukraine.
The film explores themes of famine, genocide,
ukrainian village, 1930s, holodomor.
The tone is emotional.